<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Antoine VILLATTE</title>
    <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Antoine VILLATTE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6 : Classifying Disasters on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>This project is my take on the &amp;ldquo;Real or Not ? NLP with Disaster Tweets&amp;rdquo; Kaggle competition, in which we are provided a list of tweets that can either be about a disaster or not.
All of these tweets have been detected based on keywords such as &amp;ldquo;ablaze&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s up to the competitor to build a model that determines wheter these words were used in the context of an actual event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5 : House Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>In this project, my goal was to build a predictive model to answer the House Prices Kaggle Competition, in which we are provided with diverse data concerning houses such as quality, number of bathrooms, areas, in order to predict the final sale price.
The large majority of the work was spent on exploratory data analysis and feature engineering, with some data cleaning to do in both the training and test set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4 : Next Word Predictor</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>In this project, my goal was to familiarize myself with natural language processing and use it to build a &amp;ldquo;next word&amp;rdquo; predictive model such as the ones we have on our smartphones keyboards. For that, I used a database provided by SwiftKey.
I divided this project into three parts : the App (hosted on ShinyApps), the project pitch (hosted on RPubs), and the GitHub repository that contains the App&amp;rsquo;s code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3 : Weightlifting performance machine learning</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>A machine learning project in which I used fitbit-like sensor data from gyroscopes and accelerometers to predict the performance of a weightlifting exercise.
This project goes through the following key steps :
 Raw Data gathering and cleaning Model building - RandomForest Cross validation and Testing  Link to the GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 - BMI Calculator App</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick project I made to familiarize myself with building shiny apps, especially :
 Using background plots to display on the UI Having reactive variables displayed on the plot Handling null inputs and error outputs on the UI display  I used ggplot to create the background graphs.
Link to the App
Link to the GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 - Interactive maps</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Here, I built two interactive maps to familiarize myself with the leaflet and plotly packages to make data products and presentations :
Link to an interactive GDP world map made with plotly
Link to an interactive map of France and its top 10 cities made with leaflet</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>