<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Antoine VILLATTE</title>
    <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Antoine VILLATTE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 : Next Word Predictor</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project, my goal was to familiarize myself with natural language processing and use it to build a &amp;ldquo;next word&amp;rdquo; predictive model such as the ones we have on our smartphones keyboards. For that, I used a database provided by SwiftKey.
I divided this project into three parts : the App (hosted on ShinyApps), the project pitch (hosted on RPubs), and the GitHub repository that contains the App&amp;rsquo;s code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 : Weightlifting performance machine learning</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>A machine learning project in which I used fitbit-like sensor data from gyroscopes and accelerometers to predict the performance of a weightlifting exercise.
This project goes through the following key steps :
 Raw Data gathering and cleaning Model building - RandomForest Cross validation and Testing  Link to the GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3 - BMI Calculator App</title>
      <link>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Anvil-Late.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick project I made to familiarize myself with building shiny apps, especially :
 Using background plots to display on the UI Having reactive variables displayed on the plot Handling null inputs and error outputs on the UI display  I used ggplot to create the background graphs.
Link to the App
Link to the GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>